Guide to the Ann Lauterbach Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- I. February 2001 Acquisition, 1926-1999; 24.38; (21 boxes)
  - Early Writing
    - Early school work, 1960; 2 (Box 18)
    - Victorian Literature, 1965-66 (Box 18)
    - Sketches and essays, 1960-62 (Box 18)
    - Essay or poetry on Dylan Thomas, undated (Box 18)
    - Diploma, autograph book, 1956-60 (Box 18)
  - Ephemera
    - Ephemera and miscellaneous material, 1960-90; 27 (Box 18)
    - Ephemera and miscellaneous material, 1960-96; 37 (Box 19)
    - Interview with Brodsky, undated; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 19)
      Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Brodsky/Lauterbach: Side One/Starts in middle; Side 2 - All (1 of 2 cassettes), undated; 1 (Box 19, Item barcode 39002104617395)
        Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Brodsky/Lauterbach: Side 3 - all; check Side 4, undated; 1 (Box 19, Item barcode 39002104617403)
    - Ephemera and miscellaneous material, 1960-95; 4 (Box 20)
    - Unidentified material, 1960-90
  - Oversize
    - Greeks. Original layout and art work, undated (Box 21)
    - Ephemera and miscellaneous material, 1955-90; 6 (Box 21)
    - Unidentified material, 1960-90; 27 (Box 21)
- II. May 2007 Acquisition, 1970-2000; 7.5; (8 boxes)
  May 2007 Acquisition is organized into five groupings: Resumes, Texts of Early Interviews, Projects and Correspondence 1970-1999; Project and Correspondence Files 1999-2000 and Visual Artists Files; Manuscripts of Other Authors; Other Papers; and Audiovisual Media.
  Contains: correspondence, writings, printed material, videocassettes, and other papers.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 943.
  Box 29 (videocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Resumes, Texts of Early Interviews, Projects and Correspondence 1970-1999
    - Letters to sister Jennifer early 1970s (Box 22)
    - Resume (Box 22)
    - Lauterbach Interview (Box 22)
    - Early Interview (Box 22)
    - Poetry Society Information ICA (Box 22)
    - ICA Things (Box 22)
    - Future poets (Box 22)
    - ICA Work (Box 22)
    - Texas, 1977-79 (Box 22)
    - Fund-raising, 1976 (Box 22)
    - Various correspondence, 1970-77 (Box 22)
    - Mixed, 1976-78 (Box 22)
    - Job/Career, 1976-86; 2 (Box 22)
    - Fabric Workshop, 1983 (Box 22)
    - Copy of "Greeks", 1984 (Box 22)
    - Chase, 1984 (Box 22)
    - Night Symposium, 1984 (Box 22)
    - David Rohn Ressay, 1984 (Box 22)
    - Chris Martin, 1990 (Box 22)
    - Princeton, 1985-87 (Box 22)
    - Brodsky Int., 1988 (Box 22)
    - R. Thompson, 1989 (Box 22)
    - Schuyler, 1989-90 (Box 22)
    - 28 November 1990 (Box 22)
    - Publications, 1991-92 (Box 22)
    - Annandale, Bard College (Box 22)
    - File, 1993 (Box 22)
    - Letters/File, 1993 (Box 22)
    - File 1994 (Box 22)
    - Germany/Berlin, 1993 (Box 23)
    - Publications, 1993 (Box 23)
    - Letters, 1993-94 (Box 23)
    - Letters, 1994 (Box 23)
    - Cornell, 1995-96; 2 (Box 23)
    - Ephemera, 1998 (Box 23)
    - Gardner Museum, 1998-99 (Box 23)
  - Project and Correspondence Files 1999-2000 and Visual Artists Files
    - Bard Class Papers/Work, 1998-99 (Box 23)
    - A Convergence of Birds, 1999 (Box 23)
    - Gardner A.L., 1999 (Box 23)
    - Current A.L., 1999 (Box 23)
    - Nest (website), 1999 (Box 23)
    - Barnard, 1999 (Box 23)
    - JA 99 Scribners, 2 (Box 23)
    - Ann Hamilton/Aldrich Museum, 1999 (Box 23)
    - Current Mail, 1999-2000 (Box 23)
    - Anna Moschovakis, 1999-2000 (Box 23)
    - ACA (Box 23)
    - ["L" Hanging Folder] (Box 23)
    - Found Loose (Box 23)
    - Joan Retallack (Box 23)
    - Prose (Reviews etc.) (Box 23)
    - CUNY (?) (Box 24)
    - Unidentified (Box 24)
    - Bradford Morrow (Box 24)
    - Bibliographies (Box 24)
    - Essays/Others (Box 24)
    - Groover (Box 24)
    - Melissa Meyer (Box 24)
    - Fontaine Dunn (Box 24)
    - Jim Colarusso (Box 24)
    - Refunds (Box 24)
    - Price list (Box 24)
    - Kathleen Loe (Box 24)
    - David Hannah (Box 24)
    - Willy Heeks (Box 24)
    - Dove Bradshaw (Box 24)
    - Donald Sultan (Box 24)
    - [Jesse Pollock] (Box 24)
    - [AL Printouts], 4 (Box 24)
  - Manuscripts of Other Authors
    - [Defoe - Leslie Scalapino] (Box 24)
    - Keith Waldrop, The Silhouette of the Bridge (Box 24)
    - [Kenward Elmslie] (Box 24)
    - Kenward Elmslie, Routine Disruptions (Box 24)
    - Warsh (Box 24)
    - Alan Davies (Box 24)
    - [Kenneth Rexroth] (Box 24)
    - [Charles North] (Box 25)
    - [Jackson Maclow] (Box 25)
    - [Marjorie Welish] (Box 25)
    - Wallace Shawn (Box 25)
    - Laura Moriarty (Box 25)
    - Samuel Truitt (Box 25)
    - [Tom Mandel] (Box 25)
    - Brad Morrow (Box 25)
    - Bin Ramke (Box 25)
    - D. Kovac, thesis (Box 25)
    - [Deirdre Kovac] (Box 25)
    - [Jena Osman] (Box 25)
    - John M. Dolan (Box 25)
    - Elaine Equi (Box 25)
    - [C. Harryman] (Box 25)
    - [Walter Holland] (Box 25)
    - [Vogelsang] (Box 25)
    - Galassi (Box 25)
    - [Don DeLillo] (Box 25)
    - Eli Gottlieb (Box 25)
    - Todd Colby (Box 25)
    - [Forrest Gander] (Box 25)
    - Phillip Lopate, "Bachelorhood", 3 (Box 25)
    - Peter Straub, various manuscripts, 7 (Box 26)
  - Other Papers
    - Ephemera removed from books and journals (Box 26)
    - Index card box with postcards and notecards (Box 27)
    - Rubber stamps (3) (Box 28)
  - Video Recordings
    - Barbara Guest / Ann Lauterbach Reading, The Poetry Center and The American Poetry Archive, 1995 March 23; YCALMSS736_0001; 1; 01:25:51 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002102317485)
    - Creative Writing Series: Ann Lauterbach, undated; YCALMSS736_0002; 1; 00:54:12 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002102317493)
    - Ann Lauterbach and Eileen Myles, Attitude Art, introduction by Jill Hoffman, 1987 March 12; YCALMSS736_0003; 1; 01:13:31 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002102317501)
    - The Writing Program, 1990 May 10; YCALMSS736_0004; 1 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002102317519)
    - The Writer's Voice, 10th Anniversary Season, A Poet's Bible featuring David Bradley, E. M. Broner, Ann Lauterbach, Phillip Lopate, Hugh Nissenson, Grace Schulman, David Shapiro, David Rosenberg, 1991 November 21; YCALMSS736_0005; 1; 02:02:04 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002102317527)
    - Massachusetts College of Art, Boston, Poetry at Mass Art, 1979 November; YCALMSS736_0006; 1; 00:58:20; Audio Channel #1 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002102317535)